hirepulse.com.au 2013-04-10

# Privacy Policy | HirePulse

## Overview

The HirePulse.com.au website is owned by CareerPulse Pty Ltd (hereafter “CareerPulse”). CareerPulse recognises the importance of protecting the privacy of personally identifiable information collected about our customers. For the purposes of this Privacy Statement, the term “customers” includes visitors to our website, subscribers and their team members, and users of our services and purchasers of our products. We are bound by the National Privacy Principles in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) in relation to the handling of personal information. Where appropriate we will handle personal information relying on the media exemption (but complying with the Australian Press Council Privacy Standards), related bodies corporate exemption and the employee exemption in the Privacy Act. 

## Personal Information

We collect personal information when we provide our services to you. Generally we will tell you why we are collecting information when we collect it and how we plan to use it or these things will be obvious when we collect the information. We usually collect personal information directly from you although sometimes we may use agents or service providers to do this for us. We may also acquire lists from other sources, both from other companies and from other public documents. 

In the case of team members, we typically obtain your personal information from our subscriber with whom you are associated and we operate on the assumption that you have authorised such disclosure. 

## Storage of Information

By registering for and using our services you understand that CareerPulse may collect and hold personal information provided about you or your team members indefinitely.

## Collection and Use of information

When you register for our services, we will collect your email and password information and then, following registration but prior to any advertisement, you will provide us with your: 

  1. Business name and ABN/ACN;
  2. Contact details, including street and postal address, e-mail address, website URL, and phone and fax numbers; and
  3. A description of your business.

If you register a team member, we also request the following information from you regarding that team member, not all of which must be mandatorily provided: 

  1. Title;
  2. Name
  3. Area(s) Serviced;
  4. Professions Skills; and
  5. Industry Experience.

When you register information about your team members we rely on you to inform those individuals that you are providing their personal information to CareerPulse and that you have their written consent to do so. 

When you are online, we collect information regarding the pages within our network which you visit and what you click on. As a general rule we do not collect sensitive information. However, if we do, it will usually be for the purposes of providing our products or services and if the law requires us to, we will seek your consent to collect it. 

We use your information to provide Services to you including advertising on our Site, to fulfil administrative functions associated with these products and services, for example billing, to enter into contracts with you or third parties and for marketing and client relationship purposes. We may share your information with other companies which are related to CareerPulse Pty Ltd or other businesses run by CareerPulse Pty Ltd. We or they may also use your personally identifiable information to assist us in improving our products and services and any of us might be in touch to let you know about goods, services, or promotions which may interest you. 

If you do not provide accurate personal information as requested by CareerPulse, you understand that CareerPulse may not be able to provide you with one or more products or services, or the same level of service it intends to provide to, or provides, to others. 

Except where otherwise indicated in this document, if CareerPulse intends to use your personal information for any other purpose not listed in this document, CareerPulse will seek your consent before doing so. 

CareerPulse takes all reasonable precautions to ensure that the personal information we collect, use and disclose is accurate, complete and up-to-date. However, the accuracy of this information depends to a large extent on the information you provide in your account and content. This is why we recommend that you keep your information up to date; and that you contact us with any issues if they arise. 

## Use by Third Parties

CareerPulse may disclose your information to its service providers and contractors from time to time to help us to provide and market our products and services to you. 

We may also disclose your personal information to other parties, such as our technical service providers, credit agencies, professional advisors, debt collectors, accountants, auditors, lawyers, insurers and government and regulating agencies as and when required without first contacting you. Furthermore, we may disclose such personal information to your professional advisors and/or representatives when requested in writing by you to do so. 

Please note that we are not responsible for the use that any third party may make of personal information we have provided to them in good faith and in accordance with this policy. 

## Content

**It is important that all information and documentation submitted by the subscriber to CareerPulse, including that incorporated as part of uploaded files, is checked by the subscriber to ensure its accuracy prior to submission.**

## Use of Aggregate Data

We may collect certain non-personal information to optimise our products and services, including our webpages for your computer (e.g., the identity of your Internet browser, the type of operating system you use, your IP address and the domain name of your Internet service provider). We may use such non-personal information for internal purposes, including but not limited to improving the content of our sites and assisting with the diagnosis of problems or support issues associated with our supply of the products or services. 

CareerPulse may use personally identifiable information in aggregate form to improve our goods and services including our webpages and make them more responsive to the needs of our customers. This statistical compilation and analysis of information may also be used by CareerPulse or provided to others as a summary report for marketing, advertising or research purposes. 

## Security and Storage of Personal Information

CareerPulse strives to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of personally identifiable information of our customers. We use a variety of physical and electronic security measures including restricting physical access to our offices and firewalls and secure databases to keep personal information secure from misuse, loss or unauthorised use or disclosure. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be totally secure and you accept this inherent risk. Accordingly, CareerPulse is not responsible for any event arising from unauthorised access of your personal information. 

It is your responsibility for implementing sufficient procedures and checks to satisfy the security of your computers and data from viruses, Trojans, hackers and other forms of unauthorised access by any person or program. 

If at any time you believe that the integrity of your account with CareerPulse has been breached, please contact support@hirepulse.com.au. 

From time to time, CareerPulse may also engage the services of third party providers to host the website and its associated personal information. When this occurs, CareerPulse shall endeavour to ensure that the third party provider operates in accordance with this policy and Australia’s National Privacy Principles. 

## Access to Personal Information - General

You have a right to access most personal information we hold about you and if we deny access in some circumstances we will tell you why. To request access, please contact our privacy officer as set out at the end of this document. 

Please note that we may only be able to provide you with current details of personal information we hold about you. We are not able to guarantee that we can provide you with details of personal information held about you at a particular point in time. 

## Access to Personal Information - Team Members

If you are listed as a team member for a subscriber and you believe that your personal information has been incorrectly stated in the subscriber’s advertisement, it is your responsibility to request that the subscriber amend the incorrect details and to follow the matter up with them if not corrected. 

In the event that you continue to be listed as a team member for a subscriber with whom you are no longer associated, you should advise CareerPulse of the change. Hire Pulse will then contact the subscriber concerned and advise them that they have seven (7) days to contest the matter or the team member’s details will no longer be displayed as part of their advertisement. If they contest the matter, we will contact you to advise that the matter has been contested. It is then your responsibility to contact the subscriber and settle the matter on terms that require the advertiser to amend their advertisement to remove or modify your listing as a team member of the subscriber. 

## Public Information

CareerPulse provides advertising to the general public. As such, subscribers and their team members should be aware that the information provided in their advertisements will become public information. While it is against the Terms and Conditions of Use of the CareerPulse website, CareerPulse cannot guarantee that third parties may seek to use advertised information you have provided for any purpose other than for seeking to purchase your advertised services or products. 

Any information posted on bulletin boards, communicated in chat areas and/or otherwise provided for use in any public area of the CareerPulse website becomes public information. While CareerPulse strives to protect and respect your privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose in a chat room or bulletin board. 

CareerPulse may seek to confirm personal information you provide through other publicly available sources, such as ASIC’s company and business name registers and the ATMOSS Australian on-line trade mark register. 

## Cookies

Cookies are data that a website transfers to an individual's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies can facilitate a user's ongoing access to and use of a site. They allow us to track usage patterns and to compile data that can help us improve our content and target advertising. If you do not want information collected through the use of Cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to deny or accept the Cookie feature. 

**You should note, however, that Cookies are necessary to provide you with access to your account as well as certain features or services such as site preferences.**

CareerPulse may also employ programs having similar functionality to Cookies to assist you in using the website or in us providing our services to you. 

## Online Links to Third Parties and Co-Branded Sites

CareerPulse may establish relationships with business partners that allow visitors to our Internet sites to link directly to sites operated by these partners. Some of these sites may be "co-branded" with our logo; however, these sites may not be operated or maintained by or on our behalf. These sites may collect personal information from you that may be shared with us. This Privacy Statement will apply to any personal information so shared. 

CareerPulse is not responsible for the content or practices of Web sites operated by third parties that are linked to our sites. These links are meant for the user's convenience only. Links to third party sites do not constitute sponsorship, endorsement or approval by CareerPulse of the content, policies or practices of those third party sites. Once you have left our site via such a link, you should become familiar with the applicable privacy policy of the third party site. 

## Disclosures to Law Enforcement and Regulating Agencies

Where CareerPulse receives a request for personal information about one or more of our customers from a law enforcement or regulating agency, and CareerPulse has taken advice that the request is legally valid and enforceable, CareerPulse shall disclose that information to the law enforcement or regulating agency without seeking your prior approval. Where this occurs, unless the request otherwise prohibits it, CareerPulse will contact you as soon as practicable to inform you about the request, the law enforcement or regulating agency who made the request and the personal information provided in response to the request. 

## Communication With You

CareerPulse uses personally identifiable information for essential communications, such as e-mails, account information and critical service details. However, CareerPulse will never ask you for your password via e-mail or SMS and will always identify itself in each message. 

Where CareerPulse changes its method of communicating with you, you will be advised of the reason for the change and the new method of communication through the website. 

## Children

CareerPulse’s services are not intended for children. CareerPulse will not knowingly seek personal information from any child under the age of sixteen (16). 

If a business or company is owned by a person under the age of eighteen (18), the business or company should first contact CareerPulse before becoming a subscriber of CareerPulse. Similarly, if a business or company wishes to advertise the services of a team member under the age of eighteen (18), the business or company should also first contact CareerPulse before becoming a subscriber of CareerPulse. In this manner, CareerPulse and the business or company can work together to ensure that the personal information of the minor is protected as best possible and all other legalities involving are covered. 

## Transborder Use of Information

The international nature of some of CareerPulse’s services may require CareerPulse to transfer personal information to people outside of Australia. By using such services, you consent to such transfers. 

CareerPulse will use its best efforts to comply with any law relating to the protection of personal information applicable to any international transfer of personal information. Where there is no law, or the law concerned does not provide the same level of protection to personal information as Australia’s National Privacy Principles, CareerPulse shall ensure that the international transfer of personal information and subsequent use thereof by the recipient is governed by Australia’s National Privacy Principles. 

## Other Things You Should Know About Privacy on the Internet

Remember to close your browser when you have finished your user session. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. You as an individual are responsible for the security of and access to your own computer. 

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your username and passwords and any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you are using the Internet. 

## Changes

From time to time, CareerPulse may vary this privacy policy. Such variations may, for example, be made to keep them in line with updates to its business, to comply with legislative changes or for security or technical reasons. Your continued use of the website after such variations come into effect is deemed acceptance of the new privacy policy. 

## Feedback

CareerPulse welcomes feedback of any sort on its site and services that our subscribers or visitors send to us. This information helps us to administer and improve our services and may be shared with others. Please direct any feedback to feedback@HirePulse.com.au. 

## For Further Information

Please contact our Privacy Officer by email: privacy@hirepulse.com.au to ask for access to your information or if you have a complaint concerning your information privacy or if you would like more information about our approach to privacy. 

Otherwise, further information on your rights to privacy can be found at www.privacy.gov.au.
